JONATHAN HAINES

DEVELOPER

TECH STACK

JavaScript (ECMAScript 6)

Git

TDD (Jasmine, Mocha, Chai)

RESTful API

React.js / Redux

Node.js (+ NPM)

Python 3 (+ Flask)

PHP (+ Wordpress)

HTML5

CSS3 (+ SASS and Bootstrap)

D3.js

Socket.io

Passport.js

Travis CI

Heroku

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

NOTABLE PROJECTS

WHEN AGAIN?

when-did-that-happen.herokuapp.com React/Redux app used for storing calendar dates for every user

POKEMON PYTHON

github.com/joncancode/console-adventure

Choose-your-own adventure designed for the command line

NOTE HERO

notehero.herokuapp.com

Study app for definitions memorization, built with React and Redux

CONTACT

phone: 347 678 1398

email: jc.haines19@gmail.com

SITES

jonathanhaines.me github.com/joncancode linkedin.com/in/jonathanhaines1

ABOUT

Full stack developer with 5+ years in the tech-startup scene. Passionate about education, having spent a year teaching in Asia, and now volunteering to teach JavaScript in NYC schools. When not coding, is usually found writing articles on tech

EXPERIENCE

MOXIE READER

Freelance React Developer | Dec 2017 - Present

• Execute and contribute to full-stack web development projects, with an emphasis on front end features in React and Node

THE PUBLISHER DESK

JavaScript Developer | Nov 2017 - Present

- Build client websites with WordPress/PHP, developing themes and plugins
- Manage data modeling, SQL, and database systems

SCRIPTED.ORG

Volunteer JavaScript Teacher | Aug 2017 - Present

Introduce high school students to the fundamentals of HTML, CSS,
Javascript and jQuery through ScriptEd's Foundations Course

PERSADO

Digital Marketing Campaign Engineer | Dec 2015 - Mar 2017

- Used Persado's Enterprise platform to develop and execute a series of integrated, multi-channel marketing campaigns to generate direct revenue for brands such as Sears, Under Armour, Lenovo, and others
- Partnered with the product team, project managers, customer success, and statisticians to execute multiple concurrent projects involving machine-learning on a fast-paced schedule

EDUCATION

THINKFUL

Web Development Intensive | 2017

- Completed intensive, six month course on modern full stack JavaScript development
- Collaborated with other software developers using agile methodology and TDD to create projects using React.js, Node.js, etc under the guidance of senior developers

FORDHAM UNIVERSITY

B.A. Communications (on academic scholarship) | 2010